BU Records: Erisophian Literary Society, Inclusive: 1853-1961, undated, Bulk: 1872-1928
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Erisophian Literary Society
Inclusive: 1853-1961, undated, Bulk: 1872-1928
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/88
Erisophian Literary Society, 1853 - 1932
17 document boxes and 3 oversized boxes
The Erisophian Literary Society records include administrative records, literary productions, and correspondence related to the organization. Materials include activity records, membership information, creative compositions, and other resources that provide insight about the society that existed between 1853 and 1932.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Poor.
Biography/Profile
The Erisophian Literary Society was the second literary society formed in Independence, Texas, at Baylor University. Originally established as the Caliopean Society on 1853 March 15, the name was changed to the Erisophian Literary Society several months later on October 13. Their motto was “utile dulci” and the group was nicknamed “Sophies” by the students. At the time, the two literary societies (Philomathesian and Erisophian) were the only faculty-approved extracurricular options available to students at the university. These male societies were primarily focused on debating skills but were also concerned with other subjects such as public speaking and composition. The society held meetings and hosted events featuring guest speakers. In 1857, the Erisophian Literary Society began producing the Erisophian Literary Journal, a compilation of various submissions written by members.
When Baylor University President Rufus C. Burleson moved with much of Baylor’s faculty from Independence to Waco University in 1861, the Erisophian Literary Society did not move and continued in Independence. In 1867, the society transitioned to Waco into a codependent existence with the previously established Philomathesian Literary Society. Soon after, the two societies consolidated into one Philomathesian Literary Society. However, in 1872, an effort was made to revive the Erisophian Literary Society. This was met with controversy and eventually required a consensus from the faculty to allow the reorganization of the society. The disputed restoration of the Erisophian Literary Society could be considered to be the origin of the fierce rivalry between the two groups. The independent society built upon the original foundational materials and began a new series of Erisophian Literary Journal.
The late 1800s saw the rise of four dominant literary societies at Baylor: two male societies (Philomathesian and Erisophian) and two female societies (Calliopean and Rufus C. Burleson). As the societies grew in popularity, the competition for new members increased tensions. At one point, a university rule had to be created to prohibit new students from joining a society until one week after arrival. Eventually the Philomathesian Literary Society united with the Calliopean Literary Society, which resulted in a reactionary affiliation between the Erisophian Literary Society and Rufus C. Burleson Literary Society. The societies organized public events that featured debates, speeches, readings, musical recitals, theater productions, and other entertainment. Events presented by the societies were often the major social activities at the university.
The popularity of the literary societies reached a peak during the early 1900s. Intercollegiate debating was quite popular at the time and most students at Baylor University were members of a literary society. In addition to providing a sense of group identity, the societies provided members other incentives such as private libraries. The materials in the private libraries were highly desired as the university library only maintained holdings related to coursework. The literary societies often competed against one another in heated debates about current events and campus affairs. As general interest in debate declined in the 1920s, membership in literary societies dwindled. Eventually, all of the societies donated their private libraries to the university library. As sports and other social organizations rose in popularity, the literary societies had trouble recruiting new members. The Erisophian Literary Society held its final meeting in 1932 and was the last of the four literary societies to operate at Baylor University.
Scope and Content
The BU Records: Erisophian Literary Society spans the origins of the society in 1853 through its last decade of activity. The majority of materials were created by society members; however, the collection includes some outside correspondence that somewhat represents the public perception of the society. In addition, pamphlets created by the society also provide some insight regarding how the organization’s members wanted the public to perceive the Erisophian Literary Society. Several handwritten journals documented governmental policies, regular activities of the society, and the creative output of members from 1853-1928. Certificates of membership, pledge cards, roll books, and lists of members generated by the society documented the status and number of members. Internal correspondence chronicled turnover in society management, debate results, planned events, and general recommendations by members. Library records include catalogs of inventory and circulation logs of materials. Also included are business materials used in daily operation of the society and event programs.
Arrangement
BU Records: Erisophian Literary Society was not organized, but there was an inventory.
Currently, BU Records: Erisophian Literary Society is arranged in three series: I. Administrative Records, II. Literary Productions, III. Correspondence. Series I, Administrative Records, was further arranged in six subseries: Governing Documents and Minutes, Membership Records, Internal Communication, Library Circulation, Financial Records, and Legal Records. Series II, Literary Productions, is further arranged in seven subseries: Erisophian Literary Journal, Speeches, Essays, Programs, Pamphlets, Clippings, and Printed Materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/88. Acquired 1974-04-18
Related Resources
Items in related collections
BU Records: Rufus C. Burleson Society, Inclusive: 1900-1919
BU Records: Calliopean Literary Society, Inclusive: 1885-1901, undated, Bulk: 1885-1901, undated
BU Records: Philomathesian Literary Society, Inclusive: 1859-1951, undated, Bulk: 1880-1913
Related references
Amyett, P. D. W. “A History of Literary Societies at Baylor University.” M.A. thesis, Baylor University, 1963.
Dickinson, W. C. “Baylor University: A Century of Discipline, 1845-1947.” M.A. thesis, Baylor University, 1962.
Rollolazo, S. J. “Literary Societies: The Spirit of Baylor University.” HESA Baylor History Project. Accessed 2013 June 27.
Young, R. A. “‘Sophies’ Are No More; Old Societies Reviewed.” The Daily Lariat. Waco, TX: 1932 March 18.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- History.; Baylor University. Erisophian Literary Society.
Places
Waco (Tex.) -- History.
Subjects
Baptist universities and colleges -- Texas -- Waco -- History.; College students -- Texas -- Waco -- Societies, etc.; Men -- Texas -- Waco -- Societies and clubs.
Genres
By-laws.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Essays.; Membership lists.; Minutes (Records); Programs.; Speeches.
- Administrative Records, 1853-1961, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Poor.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains the materials used in everyday operations of the organization. The materials date from the original establishment of the Caliopean Society in 1853, through the name change to the Erisophian Literary Society, their transfer to Waco, and until the last decade of the society’s existence. Included are foundational documents, meeting minutes, meeting attendance, membership documents, internal communication, private library records, financial records, and legal documents. Due to the methods used by the society to record information, some books contain multiple material types. For example, foundational documents were typically written at the beginning of a book and followed by meeting minutes. Some of the books served a dual purpose and functioned as a journal of minutes and “roll books,” which contain attendance at meetings, lists of officers, and lists of honorary members. The register’s book is listing of all members of the organization over a 61 year period. Unlike the roll books, it includes some minor biographical information related to members such as hometowns. Record books are a collection of assorted pledge materials, internal communication, financial records, correspondence, and minutes. Due to their fragile condition, the record books were disassembled to enhance preservation and increase access to those materials. The Erisophian Literary Society’s lending library was an important function of the organization, and they kept library catalogs to document what they owned. Library records recorded the distribution of materials among members. Also included in this series is the organization’s charter from the State of Texas. This series is in poor condition.
  - Governing Documents and Minutes, 1853-1928, undated; 1
    - Foundational Documents and Revisions, 1853, undated; Minutes, 1853-1860 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Revision of Foundational Documents, 1877, 1884; Membership List 1853-1893 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Roll Book and Minutes, 1860-1872 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - By-Laws, 1860; Minutes, 1876-1880 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Foundational Documents, 1872; Minutes, 1872-1878 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes 1879-1886; Membership List 1876-1883 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1886-1889 (Box 18 OVZ., Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1899-1906 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1901-1902 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1906-1914 (Box 19 OVZ., Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1906-1914 (Box 19 OVZ., Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1906-1914 (Box 19 OVZ., Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1906-1914 (Box 19 OVZ., Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Roll Book, 1912-1913; Minutes, 1914, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Draft of Constitution, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Membership Records, 1853-1961, undated; 2
    - Register’s Book, 1853-1914 (Box 20 OVZ., Folder 1)
    - Certificate of Membership, 1859; Ribbon, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Financial Records, 1878-1882 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Roll book, 1883-1889 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (1 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (2 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (3 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (4 of 45), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (5 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (6 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (7 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (8 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (9 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (10 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (11 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (12 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (13 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (14 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (15 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (16 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (17 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (18 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (19 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (20 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (21 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (22 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (23 of 25), 1888-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Roll Book, 1889-1893 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Internal Communication, 1889-1914 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (1 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (2 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (3 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (4 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (5 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (6 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (7 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (8 of 8), 1891-1895, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (1 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (2 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (3 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (4 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (5 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (6 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (7 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (8 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Record Book (9 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Record Book (10 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (11 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (12 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (13 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (14 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (15 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (16 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (17 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (18 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (19 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (20 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (21 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (22 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (23 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (24 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (25 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Record Book (26 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Record Book (27 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Record Book (28 of 28), 1893-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Roll Book, 1893-1901 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (1 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (2 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (3 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (4 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (5 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (6 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (7 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (8 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (9 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (10 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (11 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (12 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (13 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (14 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (15 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Record Book (16 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Record Book (17 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (18 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (19 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (20 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (21 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (22 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (23 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (24 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (25 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (26 of 26), 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (1 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (2 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (3 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (4 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (5 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (6 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (7 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (8 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (9 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (10 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (11 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (12 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (13 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (14 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (15 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (16 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (17 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (18 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (19 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (20 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (21 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Record Book (22 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (23 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (24 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (25 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (26 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (27 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (28 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (29 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (30 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (31 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (32 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (33 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (34 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (35 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (36 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (37 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Record Book (38 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Record Book (39 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (40 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (41 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (42 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (43 of 43), 1902-1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Research Correspondence, 1961; Membership List, 1902-1930 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (1 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (2 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (3 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (4 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (5 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (6 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (7 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (8 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (9 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (10 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (11 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (12 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (13 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (14 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (15 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (16 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (17 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (18 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (19 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (20 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (21 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (22 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (23 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (24 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Record Book (25 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Record Book (26 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (27 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (28 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (29 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (30 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (31 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (32 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Record Book (33 of 33), 1907-1928, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Roll Book, 1910-1912 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Record Book (1 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Record Book (2 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Record Book (3 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Record Book (4 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Record Book (5 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Record Book (6 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Record Book (7 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Record Book (8 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Record Book (9 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Record Book (10 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Record Book (11 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Record Book (12 of 12), 1912-1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Internal Communication, 1915-1920 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Pledge Materials, 1917-1921, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Internal Communication (1 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Internal Communication (2 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Treasurer’s Book (book cover only), undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Library Circulation, 1879-1902, undated; 3
    - Library Records, 1879 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Library Records, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Library Catalog, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 15)